NOLAN FIGUEROA

About Me

I bridge design and tech to transform how people and organizations come together.

I'm driven to solve messy problems by designing experiences that map new frontiers and build better futures.

Contact Info

+1 (915) 216-9442

https://www.astronolan.com https://linkedin.com/in/astronolan hello@astronolan.com

Top Skills

✓ Design Thinking
✓ User Experience Design
✓ Design Systems
✓ Coding Knowledge
✓ Visual Communication
✓ Design Software
✓ Research

EDUCATION

Jan 2013 – May 2015

Texas State University

BFA in Communication Design

Magna Cum Laude

Web Certificates

✓ Figma UI / UX Design Essentials, Udemy
 ✓ Human-Computer Interaction, IxDF
 ✓ Design Thinking, IxDF

EXPERIENCE

Sep 2021 – May 2023

UX Designer for Everest Design System

Charles Schwab, Remote, Full-time (40 hours weekly)

Contributed to Everest design system maintenance including component library updates, Figma migration support, and design documentation improvements. Managed docsite releases and provided mentorship to junior UX designers.

Sep 2019 - Sep 2021

Staff Engineer for Advisor Conversion Services

Charles Schwab, Hybrid, Full-time (40 hours weekly)

Designed and developed API-integrated UI components, created messaging and notifications systems, served as the go-to UX guide for product management and stakeholders.

Oct 2018 - Sep 2019

UX Designer for Advisor Conversion Services

Charles Schwab, Onsite, Full-time (40 hours weekly)

Supported START lab initiative to streamline advisor onboarding processes, contributing to 40% efficiency improvement. Facilitated UX design workshops and design thinking sessions for cross-functional teams.

Feb 2018 - Oct 2018

Senior UX/UI Designer for Lands of America

Costar Group, Onsite, Full-time (40 hours weekly)

Redesigned property listings with 20% engagement improvement. Refined navigation and UI patterns using Sketch and InVision.

Oct 2016 - Nov 2017

Product Designer for Vendor Marketplace and Communications

XO Group, Onsite, Full-time (40 hours weekly)

Optimized vendor-client interactions, increasing response rates, and drove an increase in RFQ completions to \sim 65% through UI enhancements.

More Experience

- · UX Designer, Dell Sales Application, Dell Technologies, 2015 2016
- Staff Sergeant, Security Forces, USAF, 2006 2012

10-Point Veterans' Preference & Schedule A Eligible

References given upon request